<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research Dugnads</title><link>https://research-dugnads.github.io/dugnads-hq/</link><description>Recent content on Research Dugnads</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 12:11:25 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://research-dugnads.github.io/dugnads-hq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Story Time</title><link>https://research-dugnads.github.io/dugnads-hq/storytime/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 15:12:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://research-dugnads.github.io/dugnads-hq/storytime/</guid><description>Story time! Sarah is a postdoctoral researcher in an astrophysics group. She has been using research software and writing her own code to run and analyse simulations for years but not had much formal training. She wants to improve her coding skills and thinks the rest of her group would benefit from this too. She has heard someone at a conference talking about a &amp;lsquo;Research Dugnad&amp;rsquo; so she emails them and asks for more information.</description></item><item><title>Invite an RSE</title><link>https://research-dugnads.github.io/dugnads-hq/invite_an_rse/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 11:17:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://research-dugnads.github.io/dugnads-hq/invite_an_rse/</guid><description>Plenty of institutions now have Research Software Engineers (RSEs), people who combine an understanding of research with a knowledge of software engineering methods and practice. If you know of an RSE on your campus or in your network, you may consider bringing them in on your Research Dugnad to help out.
How can an RSE help us? Research Software Engineers can help with any of the process or practice issues you have in writing, maintaining, or distributing the software you produce in your research.</description></item><item><title>What do we do in our dugnad?</title><link>https://research-dugnads.github.io/dugnads-hq/example_activities/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 11:07:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://research-dugnads.github.io/dugnads-hq/example_activities/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s entirely up to you! This is time to collectively improve your shared environment. Your group probably already has ideas about what good parts of your software and practices could become great, and what&amp;hellip;not-so-good things there are that could also be improved. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already explicitly discussed this, you might want to set aside half an hour at the beginning of your dugnad to discuss what there is to be done and to record a list of activities: that&amp;rsquo;s actually how we built this template dugnad!</description></item><item><title>Motivation</title><link>https://research-dugnads.github.io/dugnads-hq/motivation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 10:59:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://research-dugnads.github.io/dugnads-hq/motivation/</guid><description>Why would you run a Research Dugnad? What is a dugnad? &amp;lsquo;Dugnad&amp;rsquo; is a Norwegian word meaning voluntary collective work, for example, shared housing residents coming together to work on shared garden space, or young school children tidying and decorating their classroom. In 2004 it was voted Norwegian word of the year, and in 2020 was used to encourage the people of Norway to come together as a community to fight the pandemic.</description></item></channel></rss>